mythings.com 2010-03-10

# MyThings - Your privacy is protected and your records are secure

This Privacy Policy and the User Agreement (and, if you register as a Member of the Website, the Terms of Membership which you enter into as part of the registration process) together govern your use of this website (the "Website"). By using the Website, you signify your acceptance to this Privacy Policy and to us processing your personal data in accordance with the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree to this Privacy Policy, you should not use the Website. If you have further questions or comments about our privacy policies or practices after reading this Privacy Policy, please contact us at [info@mythings.com](mailto:info@mythings.com?subject=Question%20or%20Comment%20about%20the%20Privacy%20Policy) or mail us at:

MyThings Inc.

5519 Amesfield Ct.

Rockville MD 20853

U.S.A.

**Scope**

We take your privacy very seriously. This Privacy Policy explains how we collect your personal data on the Website, how we protect such data, and the choices you have concerning our use of such data. This Privacy Policy governs the URL [http://www.mythings.com](http://www.mythings.com/). MyThings professionals control the information about you described in this document.

Please read this Privacy Policy carefully. For the purposes of this Privacy Policy, "we", "us", and "our" means MyThings Inc. ("MyThings"). This Privacy Policy applies only to information collected by the Website. We are not responsible for the privacy practices of websites that are operated or owned by third parties. Please assist us in protecting your privacy by reading our Be Safe guidelines in the Account section of the website, and by contacting us and/or the Webmaster immediately by clicking on the Report Misuse link at the bottom of every page and sending in the form, or by using the [Contact Us](http://www.mythings.com/contact.aspx) information on the Website if you become aware of any abuse of your privacy by any person, if you are unhappy with the treatment of your personal information or if you are asked to provide any information that you consider to be inappropriate.

This Privacy Policy is effective upon acceptance for new users and is otherwise effective on Thursday, December 7, 2006.  We may from time to time review and revise our privacy practices and will post any changes to this Privacy Policy here. Please refer back to this Privacy Policy on a regular basis. Your continued use of the Website following changes posted to this Privacy Policy will mean that you accept those changes.

**Collection of Personal Data**

Personal data is information that identifies you or can be used to identify or contact you, e.g. your name, e-mail address, address, phone number, credit card number, card security code or card expiration date (when applicable) (which will be used to process orders and provide order notification); All of the foregoing shall be collectively referred to as "Personal Data". The only Personal Data that MyThings requires from you when you register on the Website is your e-mail address. However, you may voluntarily provide additional Personal Data to the Website by registering information on your personal profile, by posting messages on our community boards, chat rooms or other message areas or by providing information in connection with payment for any goods or services that you purchase on the Website. MyThings will collect all Personal Data that you provide to the Website or to MyThings, but we will not sell, share, license, trade or rent your Personal Data other than as specified in this Privacy Policy. MyThings does not collect any sensitive personal data from users.

Any information included in messages or comments that you have posted on the Website's community boards, chat rooms or other message areas or included on a personal profile which you have designated to be "public" may be viewed by anyone who accesses the Website and cannot be subject to any expectations of privacy.

Information that you provide to the Website is accessible to any site visitor who knows your username and password. For this reason, please safeguard your username and password carefully and do not disclose it to any other person.

You do not have to provide us with any Personal Data to visit the Website. However, users who have not registered on the Website may not be able to visit all sections of or use all services offered on the Website.

**Transactions for Goods or Services**

When you make a purchase through the Website, your credit card number or other payment account number, billing address and other information related to such purchase (collectively, "Payment Information") shall be collected from you by MyThings or by any third party (such as Paypal), and MyThings and/or such third party may use such Payment Information in order to fulfill your purchase. We may also provide such Payment Information provided by you to third parties as necessary to complete your purchase (for example, to process your credit card or payment account number).

From time to time, MyThings may employ third-party contractors to collect Personal Data on its behalf to provide email delivery; product; promotional fulfillment; contest administration; credit card processing; shipping or other services available through the Website. When requesting these services, you may be asked to supply your name, mailing address, telephone number, email address and/or credit card (including card security code, expiration date and any additional relevant information) to our contractors.

If you purchase a product or service from MyThings or from a third party provider advertised on the Website ("Third Party Provider"), the Personal Data that you submit in connection with the transaction (including, without limitation, your credit card information) will be collected in one of two ways. Either (a) you will be redirected to the Third Party Provider's website and your Personal Data will be collected directly by the relevant Third Party Provider, or (b) you will be redirected to the website of a third party processor (Paypal, for example) and your Personal Data will be collected directly by such processor, or MyThings will share the relevant Personal Data with said processor as necessary for the processor to provide its service; The third party processor shall verify your credit card and your Personal Data and advise whether the transaction is approved. MyThings cannot and will not take responsibility for the success or security of transactions undertakes or processed by third party processor and/or Third Party Provider. MyThings will use reasonable efforts that it will be made clear whether you are still on the Website or whether you have been redirected to a Third Party Provider's website. Please view the [Links section](http://www.mythings.com/privacy.aspx#links) of this Privacy Policy in relation to third party websites.

We collect information relating to the transactions you have entered into on or using the Website to enable you to view your transaction history and details of the Third Party Providers with whom you have previously dealt. If you do not want us to collect this information, please "opt-out" by unchecking the appropriate box on the relevant service request form. MyThings does not collect credit card details and accordingly, such details are not stored by MyThings. All credit card details are collected and stored by any third party processor (such as Paypal) and/or by any Third Party Provider, as the case may be. 

**Messages**

The Website offers an internal e-mail service to registered users known as “Messages.” If you register as a member of MyThings, your self-created screen name will be accessible to other registered members on the Website only if you have made one or more of your things public. If your screen name is accessible to other registered users, other registered users may contact you directly via Messages. If you post information in your profile and designate it as public, other registered members of the Website will be able to view only the information you have designated as public. If you do not want your MyThings screen name to be accessible to other registered users of the Website or if you wish not to be contacted directly by registered users, you may prevent access to your screen name by not making any of your things public.

You may make your email address searchable so that other people who know your email address can search for you to see if you are Member and may invite you to join their networks of friends. If you do not wish to be contacted or searched in this way you may adjust your profile.

**Protection of Children's Online Privacy**

MyThings understands the importance of protecting children's privacy, especially in an online environment. The Website is not intentionally designed for or directed at children under 14 years of age. It is MyThings’ policy to never knowingly collect or maintain information about individuals under the age of 14.

**Collection of Monitoring Data and Use of Tracking Tools**

In addition to Personal Data, MyThings may collect and/or track information that by itself cannot be used to identify or contact you, e.g., demographic information, domain names, computer type, browser types, screen resolution, IP address and other anonymous statistical data involving the use of the Website ("Monitoring Data"). We use Monitoring Data to help us understand who uses the Website and to improve and market the Website.

To enhance the Internet experience on the Website, MyThings may use various Internet technologies such as 'cookies,' ‘action tags,’ ‘web bugs,’ ‘.gif tags,’ and 'JavaScript' (together, "Tracking Tools"). Tracking Tools are files or tools that are placed on your computer in order to identify your Web browser and the activities of your computer on the Website. MyThings uses these technologies to customize and enhance the Internet experience of individual users. When you revisit the Website, MyThings may recognize you by a Tracking Tool and customize your experience accordingly. For example, once you have completed the sign up process, you will have the option of agreeing to MyThings remembering you and, if you agree, a cookie will be used to avoid having you sign up again. You may decline Internet cookies, if any, by using the appropriate feature of your Web browser software, if available. If cookies are disabled, however, all features of the Website may not operate as intended. Information about the procedure you are required to follow in order to disable cookies can be found on your Web browser’s help feature.

We believe Tracking Tool technologies add value to the user experience, and the information resulting from these technologies is not sold or otherwise made available to third parties by MyThings.

You may encounter 'cookies' or other similar devices on certain pages of the Website that are placed there by third parties.  For example, if you view a webpage created by a user, there may be a cookie placed within that webpage. We do not control the use of cookies by third parties.

**Use and Disclosure of Data Collected**

MyThings may use Personal Data it collects for editorial and feedback purposes, marketing and promotion, statistical analysis of users’ behaviour, product development, delivering products and services, providing customer support, customizing and improving the content and layout of the Website, completing business transactions, administering individual accounts and meeting government regulatory requirements such as sales tax collection. Monitoring Data may be used for internal or external purposes such as researching and identifying market segments and needs. MyThings will disclose Personal Data to comply with valid legal processes such as a search warrant, subpoena, or court order, or to protect our rights and property. We will disclose Personal Data when we believe in good faith that the law requires such disclosure. MyThings also will disclose your Personal Data when necessary to comply with applicable laws, rules or regulations, when you have expressly consented to such disclosure, or when necessary to preserve MyThings' legal rights in the Website’s content.

MyThings reserves the right to transfer your Personal Data within the MyThings group (the details of which can be found on the [Contact Us](http://www.mythings.com/contact.aspx) page on the Website), or to successors to the relevant part of any of MyThings' businesses. MyThings also reserves the right to transfer your Personal Data when necessary to enable an independent contractor to assist with the operation of the Website.

Except as specifically set forth above, MyThings will not disclose any of your Personal Data to third parties.

**Marketing**

MyThings does not sell or rent your Personal Data to third parties for marketing purposes without your explicit content. We may combine your Personal Data with information we collect from other companies (such as demographic data) to improve and personalize our services.

**Your Choices Regarding Personal Data Collection and Use**

If you are a member of the Website, you may "opt-out" of MyThings sending its own promotional correspondence to you, and/or "opt-in" to MyThings sending Third Party Providers' promotional correspondence to you at your internal MyThings e-mail ("Messages") address by selecting your preferred options on the email and messaging options link within Account, or at any time in the future by changing the "User Profile" of your account, or by contacting MyThings via postal mail, e-mail, or telephone at the address set out in the "Contact Information" section below. Except as described in the section above entitled "Use of Data Collected," MyThings will not share any Personal Data with a third party without giving you the opportunity to "opt-in" and give or deny us permission to do so.

Upon request via [postal mail, e-mail, or telephone](http://www.mythings.com/contact.aspx), MyThings will provide to you a summary of any Personal Data retained by MyThings regarding you. You may modify, correct, change or update Personal Data that MyThings has collected via the Website. You may refuse to have your Personal Data processed by MyThings or you may request that your Personal Data be removed from MyThings' database by contacting MyThings via [postal mail or e-mail](http://www.mythings.com/contact.aspx) provided, however, that such requests may result in you ceasing to be a registered user of the Website. You should be aware that it may not be technologically possible to remove or verify each and every record of information you have provided to us from our system. The need to back-up our systems to protect information from inadvertent loss means that a copy of your Personal Data may exist in archived systems. However, promptly after receiving your request, all Personal Data stored in databases we actively use and other readily searchable media will be updated, corrected, changed, deleted or confirmed to you, as applicable, as soon as reasonably practicable. MyThings will take all commercially reasonable steps to remove any Personal Data stored on our systems if you so request.

**Links**

The Website may contain links to other Internet websites. MyThings does not endorse, and is not responsible for, the privacy practices or the content of these websites. You should review the applicable privacy policies in connection with your use of such third party websites.

**Security Measures**

MyThings has established reasonable precautions to protect collected Personal Data from loss, misuse, unauthorized access, disclosure, alteration or destruction, which include contractual, administrative, physical, and technical steps. Technical measures include use of firewall protection and encryption technology where appropriate. Although MyThings takes reasonable precautions to assess the reliability of such technology, it relies on the statements of the vendors of those products and services as part of its security evaluation. Please note that while MyThings has endeavoured to create a secure and reliable site for users, the confidentiality of any communication or material transmitted to/from MyThings or the Website cannot be guaranteed. Please note that e-mail communications will not necessarily be secure; accordingly you should not include credit card information or other sensitive information in your e-mail correspondence with us.

**Export of Personal Data**

By using the Website, you acknowledge and consent to the fact that Personal Data provided by you or collected by us through your use of the Website is stored and processed by us in the United States where data protection laws may not afford the same level of protection as those of the country in which you are located (particularly for users located in the European Economic Area (“EEA”)).  You also acknowledge and consent to the fact that we may, at our discretion, store and process such data in other countries (including countries outside the EEA) where data protection laws may not afford the same level of protection as those of the country in which you are located.

**Contact Information for MyThings**

Questions or concerns regarding MyThings' data protection practices should be addressed to:

**MyThings, Inc.**

Attention: Data Protection Practices

5519 Amesfield Ct.

Rockville MD 20853

U.S.A.

If you choose to contact MyThings via e-mail about this policy, please mark the subject heading of your e-mail “Privacy Enquiry”.

We shall keep a copy of this Privacy Policy and if, at any time, you would like to see a copy of it, you should write to the following address:

**MyThings, Inc.**

**Attention: Data Protection Practices**

5519 Amesfield Ct.

Rockville MD 20853

**U.S.A.**

**BY USING THE WEBSITE AND/OR BECOMING A MEMBER OF MYTHINGS, YOU SIGNIFY YOUR ACCEPTANCE OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY AND OF US PROCESSING YOUR PERSONAL DATA IN ACCORDANCE WITH THE TERMS OF THIS PRIVACY POLICY. IF YOU DO NOT AGREE TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY, YOU SHOULD NOT USE THE WEBSITE. YOUR CONTINUED USE OF THE WEBSITE FOLLOWING THE POSTING OF CHANGES TO THIS PRIVACY POLICY WILL MEAN THAT YOU ACCEPT THOSE CHANGES.**

**SPECIAL NOTICE TO CALIFORNIA RESIDENTS**

**As a California resident, you have certain rights under state law that relate to the sharing of your personal information with third parties for their own direct marketing purposes. MyThings has chosen to comply with California law SB-27 in the following way:**

**First, individual customers who reside in California and who have provided their personal information to MyThings may request (no more than once per calendar year) information about our disclosures of certain categories of personal information to any third parties. To make such a request, please send an e-mail to info@mythings.com and provide us with your name, address, and e-mail address. Within thirty days of receiving such a request, MyThings will provide a list of the categories of personal information disclosed to third parties during the immediately preceding calendar year, along with the names and addresses of such third parties. All inquiries relating to California SB 27 should be directed to us at[ info@mythings.com](mailto:info@mythings.com?subject=California%20SB%2027). **
